All the Beauty and the Bloodshed is a documentary
film directed by Laura Poitras.
The life of internationally renowned artist and activist Nan Goldin is told through her slideshows, intimate interviews,
ground-breaking photography, and rare footage of her personal fight to hold the Sackler family accountable for the overdose crisis.
Self, played by Nan Goldin.
Self, played by Marina Berio.
Self, played by Noemi Bonazzi.
Self, played by Harry Cullen.
Self, played by Megan Kapler.
Self, played by Annatina Miescher.
All the Beauty and the Bloodshed is a 2022 American biographical documentary
film about photographer, artist, and activist Nan Goldin.
The film is produced, co-edited and directed by Laura Poitras, and tackles Goldin's life through her advocacy during the HIV/AIDS crisis
in the ‘80s, and her fight against the Sackler family for their role in the current opioid epidemic in the United States.
Poitras, a long-time friend and fan, stated that "Nan's art and vision has inspired my work for years, and has influenced generations of filmmakers."
The film premiered on September 3, 2022, at
the 79th Venice International Film Festival, where it was awarded the Golden Lion, making it the second documentary (following Sacro GRA in 2013) to win the top prize at Venice.
It also screened at the 2022 New York Film Festival, where it was the festival's
centerpiece film and for which Goldin designed two official posters.
The film was received with critical acclaim, and was
released in cinemas by Neon on November 23, 2022.
At the 95th Academy Awards, the film was nominated for Best Documentary Feature.
The film then went on to win a Peabody Award at the 84th ceremony for "capturing the zeal of
an artist eager to use her work to create a new vision for and of the world."
The film explores themes of aids, photographer,
photography, political activism, interview.